Summer 下次我们躲在克罗基恩回音巢时
Summer, next time we’re hiding in a Colorkian echo nest,
你能行行好把手机铃声关掉吗
can you do me a favor and turn your ringer off?
这首歌有名字叫"活在当下" Morty
It’s called “carpe diem,” Morty.
自己去搜搜吧 - 你才去搜搜呢
Look it up. -You look it up!
你 你自己都 你自己都不懂这个词什么意思
Y-Y-You don’t even -- You don’t even know what it means!
因为废物才会去查这查那
That’s because losers look stuff up
而我们其他人都活在当下
while the rest of us are carpin’ all them diems.
好好听你姐姐说的 Morty
Listen to your sister, Morty.
生活就是要敢于冒险
To live is to risk it all.
否则你就称不上生命 只是一团
0therwis e, you’re just an inert chunk
随机排布的分子
of randomly assembled molecules
在宇宙之中随波逐流
drifting wherever the universe blows you.
啊 不好意思 Jerry 没看着你在这儿
Oh, I’m sorry. Jerry, I didn’t see you there.
刚刚说的你听见了多少
H-How much of that did you hear?
全听见了 你刚明明盯着我说的
All of it. You were looking right at me.
我就是想过来和孩子们道个别
I just wanted to say goodbye to the kids.
很好 待在车道上就好
Cool. Just stay in the driveway.
灭杀机器人激活了 我把你从白名单里撤掉了
The kilibots are live, and I took you off the white list.
我们每隔一个周末都还是会再见的 对吧
W-Weil see you every other weekend, though, right?
肯定会的 Morty
Absolutely, Morty.
而且你妈妈的律师说
A-And your Mom’s lawyer says
如果判决中我得到足够的损害赔偿
if I can get enough in the settlement,
他可以帮我打官司争取单独监护权
he can help me sue for full custody.
那也蛮好的
Th-That’ll be nice.
呃 Summer 爸爸要走了 - 拜拜 爸
Uh, Summer, Dad’s leaving. -Bye, Dad.
Rick 你是不是说过要我帮忙
Rick, didn’t you say you needed my help
马上去别的什么地方探险来着
on an adventure immediately somewhere else --
哪都无所谓 要人命也无所谓
I don’t care -- even if it might kill us?
我没说 但你们要真这么不对付
I did not, but if you’re really that alienated,
我也愿意利用下这个机会 也就随便什么人 教会 军队
I’m as willing to exploit it as the next guy, church, army,
奥林匹克体操教练这种程度的愿意吧
or Olympic gymnastics trainer.
你准备好了我就好了
I’m ready when you are.
我昨天就准备好了
Bitch, I was ready yest-
拜拜 宝贝
Bye, sweetie.
那么 我 我最好
Well, I-I better...
去吧 听着挺要紧的
Sure. Sounds important.
你要找孩子们的话
If you’re looking for our kids,
你爸刚开了一个传送门
your father did a-a portal, uh...
行吧
Okay.
废物
WIND: [Soft voice] Loser.
什么
What?
有人吗
Hello?
Morty 快打那个莫霍克头的人
Morty, shoot the Mohawk guy!
他们全都是这个发型
-They all have Mohawks! -High fade,
高平头 黄绿色缀蓝色 顶上做了层次
chartreuse with cyan highlights, layered on Top.
快打他
Shoot him!
炸死他们
Light them up.
妈的 干点事 Morty
Fuck! Get in the game, Morty!
把你的酒壶给我
Give me your flask!
妈呀 Summer厉害了
Holy shit! Summer for the win!
我真他妈喜欢后末世世界的地球
I fucking love post-apocalyptic versions of Earth!
要到了
Here we go!
同位素322
IsoTope 322.
这玩意儿可猛了 Morty
This stuffs so powerful, Morty,
同位素465在这东西面前就跟同位素317一样
it makes IsoTope 465 look like IsoTope 317.
嗯哼 很好
Uh-huh, yeah.
那它有猛到让那些家伙杀不掉我们吗
Is it powerful enoughto keep those guys from murdering us?
Summer - 等会儿
Summer! -Hold on.
我要试点新花样
I want to try something.
Rick 咱俩能别撇下我姐姐就跑吗
Rick, can we not leave without my sister?
你有无穷多个姐姐 Morty
Ugh. You have infinite sisters, Morty.
但我也不是说我就想剩下一整天
I mean, n-not that I want to spend the rest of my day
都花在再给你找个姐姐上
looking for another one.
Summer宝贝儿 走吧
“Sum-sum,” let’s go!
外公可只有这一小会儿担心你的安全哟
Grandpa’s concern for your safety is fleeting!
我要拿你的血做身体乳
Your blood will be my lotion.
哇啊噢 酷
Whoa. That was cool.
杀了我吧
Kill me, please.
可以 我本来就要杀的
Okay, but not because you told me to.
Summer
Summer!
好吧 愈发黑化了
Okay. Getting darker.
天呐 Summer
Jesus Christ. Summer!
噢 又来了
Aw, come on.
把手和肩上扛的小家伙举高
Hands and little shoulder-mounted dudes
放到我能看见的地方
where I can see them.
我是何血崩
I am Hemorrhage.
你们除掉了我们中的弱者 让我们变得强大
You have removed weak blood from us and made us stronger.
我们应该合作 一起尽情享受追猎弱者的快乐
We can combine our strength and feast on the weak together.
你你你到底在说些什么
Wh-Wh-What in the hell are you saying?
他想让我们加入 这样他们就不用拼命追杀我们了
They don’t have to keep trying to kill us if we join them.
一群孬逼 - 你最近到底怎么了
They’re basically pussies. -What is your deal lately?
行吧 咱爽爽
All right, let’s get sloppy.
哦 哇喔
Oh, whoa.
呃 呃 那个 呃
Uh, uh, what’s, uh --
你背后那个小玩意儿是什么
What’s that little bauble you got back there?
挺挺挺有意思的
Th-Th-That’s interesting.
那是我们的发光石
That is our glowing rock.
我们带着它是为了渎神
We carry it with us for desecration,
为了提醒我们这世上根本没有神明
to remind us there are no gods.
孩子们 峰回路转呐
Kids, weird pitch.
让我们的新生活从这里开始吧
Let’s have this be our new life.
让我们在后末世世界捡垃圾
Let’s be post-apocalyptic scavengers!
好啊 - 什么
Okay. -What?
外公 有些死亡追猎者准备去
Grandpa, some of the Death Stalkers
曾经叫西雅图的地方
are going to what used to be Seattle
猎杀曾经叫人类的东西
to hunt what used to be people.
我也要去 - 挺好的 记得多喝水
I’m going. -Sounds good. Stay hydrated.
听着 Rick Summer最近都跟疯了似的
Listen, Rick, Summer’s been acting pretty crazy lately.
离婚的事对她影响蛮大的
You know, I mean, I-I think the divorce is affecting her.
而且 我觉得她现在
And, you know, I don’t think this is
不适合待在这种地方
a great place for her to be right now.
哦 少站在道德制高点上了 山顶冷不冷啊
Oh, get off your high horse, Professor Ski Lodge.
这个世界可能很粗野
This world may be rough around the edges,
但它有它的魅力所在
but it’s got its charms.
二头肌还是股四头肌
WAR CHEF: Bicep or quadricep?
呃 二头肌
Uh bicep.
真的吗 Rick
Seriously, Rick?
直接告诉我留在这的原因
Is it really easier to eat human flesh
真的比吃人肉还难吗
than to just tell me why we’re still here?
并不 好吧 我跟你说实话
No. Okay, I‘ll level with you.
看到那块绿石头没有 Morty
You see that green rock, Morty?
这大概有二十磅
It's about 20 pounds of the stuff
之前我那么费力才找到一小片
I was getting all hard for a flake of.
同位素322
IsoTope 322.
这东西有个二十磅
Well, having a 20-pound boulder of it
比只有一小片强多了
is better than having a flake.
我稍后再向你解释其中的数学原理 但
I can explain the math to you later, but --
Summer刚刚和一群陌生人走了
Summer just ran off with strangers
那群人的名字以"死亡"开头
that have “Death” in their name,
以"追捕者"(跟踪狂)结尾好嘛
and the rest of their name was “Stalkers.”
哈 正好能让她宣泄一下
Huh, could be therapeutic for her.
她最近的行为太疯狂了 Morty
She has been acting pretty crazy lately, Morty.
我是说 她的父母要离婚了
I mean, her parents are going through a divorce --
Rick 这是我刚才 算了
God damn it, Rick, that’s what I -- Fine.
你快拿走这蠢石头 我去找Summer
Just grab the stupid thing while I grab her,
赶紧离开这鬼地方
and let’s get the “F” out of “H.”
不 不 不 Morty 他们看得太紧
No, no, no. Morty, there’s too much heat on the bogey.
我要你引开他们的注意力
I need you to distract the camp.
什么叫"引开" 他们连对方都吃
“Distract”? They eat each other.
我 我怎么吸引他们的注意啊
What -- What do you want me to do to get their attention,
表演木偶戏吗
put on a puppet show?
方向对了 方式要改 Morty
Right idea, wrong genre, Morty.
在这里 咱们得
The equivalent here would be...
嘿 那个雷电斗技场是拿来用的
Hey, you guys ever use that Thunderdome,
还是拿来看的啊
or do you just put it up for decoration?
你是说鲜血斗技场吗
Uh, you mean the Blood Dome?
这句你留给语义斗技场吧 E.B.怀特(美国作家 工于语言)
Save it for the Semantics Dome, E.B. White.
喔 喷得妙
-Ohh, burn!
重点问题是
The important question is,
有谁想来和我的吞脊侠较量较量
who wants to take a poke at my man Spine Eater here?
咱们斗技场里见咯
I guess Ill see your asses in that dome!
Rick 你搞什么啊
Rick, what the hell, man?
你疯了吗
Wh-What are you, out of your mind?
Morty 不怕 有我帮你作弊
Morty, relax. You’re gonna be a ringer.
来这儿
Come here.
这个装置能提取和再分配肌肉记忆
This device extracts and redistributes muscle memory.
我给注射你十年荒野格斗的经验
I’m giving your body a 10-year course in wasteland combat
一次一只胳膊腿儿 - 嗷
one limb at a time. -Ow!
这些个胳膊腿儿都不是同一个人的
I’m working with a mixed bag here,
所以你可能不是很协调 Morty 啊
so you may not have perfect coordination, Morty -- Ugh!
嘿 - 不是我干的
Hey! -I-I didn’t do that!
好吧 真让人激动
Okay, this is exciting.
我们对肌肉记忆有了新发现
We’re making some discoveries about muscle memory.
哦 救命 救命
Ooh! Help! Help!
真棒
Oh, sweet, man!
就此开始啦 宝贝儿们
And so it begins, my pretties!
哦 天呐 停下 停下 这太可怕了
Oh, God! STop! STop! This is horrible!
适应磨合一下 Morty
Just stick and move, Morty!
让他筋疲力尽
Wear him out!
你们为啥都穿得像在搞主题公园的特技表演
How come you guys dress like you’re in a theme-park stunt show,
但是这些人却穿着卡其装和冰球服
but these guys wear khakis and hockey jerseys?
大爆爆以后 一些人适应了新世界
After the boom-boom, some adapted to the new truth,
而一些人选择在爆爆洞旁挤作一团
and some chose to huddle near the boomy holes,
执着于世界未变的谎言
clinging to the lie of the before-fore times.
镭雷射线让他们腐化
The raidy-rays rotted them away,
只留下他们对广告牌牌上的广告告的爱
leaving only their love for the vert-vert-isements on billyboards.
天呐
Jesus Christ.
大爆爆也炸毁了你们所有的词词书吗
Did the boomy-booms blow up all your wordy-word books?
你是说字典吗
You mean dictionaries?
我想在大爆爆前 我还是个孩子
I think I was a child before the boom-booms.
我以前可能长得像这样
I think I looked like this.
想尿在他上面吗
Want to piss on him?
你是我肚子里的蛔虫吗
Get out of my head.
哈哈 喔
ELI: Ha ha! Whoo!
难以置信
Unbelievable!
一个新的冠军
A new champ!
好了 打住
Okay, no more!
他还想打
And he wants more!
不 我没有
No, I don’t!
快来人 让它停下
Someone make this sTop!
先生 请离开这里 否则你会死掉的
Mister, please get out of here, or you’re gonna die!
我跟这事毫不相干
I have nothing to do with this!
Morty
Morty.
你为什么要这样
Why would you want this to happen?
你明明只需要滚开就行了
All you had to do was go away!
别再站在车道上说什么监护权了
STop standing in the driveway talking about custody!
要么你就告诉她你不想离婚
And either tell her you want to stay married
要么好好自己生活 但是不管做什么
or get on with your life, but whatever you do,
别孬了 做条汉子
sTop being a baby and act like a man!
谢谢
Thank you.
Morty 太棒了
Morty, that was amazing!
这是我弟弟
This is my brother!
没有家庭关系很重要的意思
Not that family means anything!
这个家庭是的
This family does.
好了 干得好 冠军
All right. Good job, champ.
嗯 我能和你们俩孩子在那儿说几句吗
Urn, can I talk to you kids for a second over yonder?
Rick 我 我觉得我在这儿挺有突破的
Rick, I-I-I think l’rn breaking through to something here.
我 我们能不能先别离开
C-Can we not leave just yet?
离开 - 我不离开
Leave? -I’m not leaving.
这里没有离开一说
There is no “leave.”
要么团结一致 要么针锋相对
We are united, or we are enemies.
哦 大块头 不 没人要离开
Oh, big guy, no. Nobody’s leaving.
别傻了
Don’t be stupid.
我们就爱团结一致
We love being united.
我们爱辐射和毛线虫病
We love the radiation, the trichinosis.
我们这辈子都不走了
We’re in it for life,
我估计这儿的"一辈子"平均也就是二十年
which I assume is around 20 years, average.
我想跟我的外孙们独处一小会
I just need a quick aside with my grandkids,
距离无关人士四十码远就行
about 40 yards from anyone else.
绿石头不见了
Hey, the Green Rock is gone!
哦不 - 我懂
Oh, no! -Uh, I know.
我建议我们三人一组分头去找
Why don’t we all split up and look for it in groups of three?
孩儿们
Kids?
噢
Ohh.
我们马上回来
We’ll be right back.
外公 你在做傻事
Grandpa, you’re being stupid!
投降吧 我的朋友会施与你仁慈
Just surrender, and our friends will give you mercy!
滚你的吧 Summer
Kiss my ass, Summer!
你的朋友没有仁慈 他们弱爆了
Your friends have no mercy! They’re lame!
死亡猎手们 给我活扒他的皮
Death Stalkers, bring me his flesh leather!
不好意思 能不杀他吗
Sorry, but can we not kill him?
就不能把他关起来吗
C-Can we just take him prisoner?
等等 不是我说了算的吗
When did I lose control here?
你们俩死孩子
Listen to me -- Both of you kids
听我的 离开这里
need to get out of this environment
让我们好好面对你们父母离婚的事
so we can properly deal with your parents’ divorce!
不然嘞 我还有把传送枪
Alternatively, I have a freaking portal gun,
我就先撤了 你俩在这儿度过余生吧
and I can leave the two of you here forever!
为啥只有这么绝对的选项
Why does it have to be such a dramatic choice?
我们就不能在这儿度度周末
Can’t we arrange a thing where we spend weekends here
或者 或者回家洗衣服
or -- or visit home to do laundry?
老子不陪你们玩了
All right, you know what?
去你的吧
Fuck it!
我的身躯是铬合金
My body is chrome!
我的血是汽油
My blood is gasoline!
错 就是一般血
Nope. Regular blood.
爸 - 嗨 乖女儿
Dad? -Hi, sweetie.
孩子们呢 - 他们没跟你一块吗
Where are the kids? -Oh, th-they aren’t with you?
我以为他们跟你在一块呢
I thought they were with you.
哦你知道吗 我刚想起来
Oh, y-you know what? Uh, I just remembered.
他们出去办事了
They’re out doing something
非常正常 非常适宜儿童
completely ordinary and kid-related.
别慌 - 我不慌 只是
Don’t panic. -Not panicked at all. Just --
天哪 离婚这事儿把孩子们怎么了
Oh, God, what’s the divorce doing to the kids?
把我怎么了 我是不是犯了个错误
What’s it doing to me? Did I make a mistake?
绝对没错
Not a mistake, no!
不是说你离不离婚 于我有什么好处
I mean, not that I have a horse in this race,
但是离婚这个决定 棒
but this divorce decision, listen -- mwah! --
对你好 对孩子们也好
good for you, good for the kids.
实话说 我觉得他们在茁壮成长
I mean, honestly, I think that they’re flourishing.
你会懂的 等你看见他们你就懂了
I mean, you’ll see, when -- when -- when you see them,
真的是茁壮成长
that -- that they’re totally flourishing.
哇哈哈 去死吧
Booyah! Fuck you, pal!
谁还想来
Who else wants some?
今天谁还想来给爷干
Who wants to be my pussy of a dad today?
嘿怎么啦
Hey, what’s -- what’s wrong, man?
你不是在我身上会慢慢不行吧
You’re not getting weak on me, are you?
啥
What?
等等
Wait a minute.
咋啦 垃圾
What’s the matter, you piece of crap?
从来没见过你全家被烧死吗
Haven’t you ever watched your family burn to death before?
吃鞭子吧
Now I’m gonna whip you. Huh!
不可能
It can’t be. It can’t be!
It can’t be!
我只是奉命行事 - 哇 哇
l was just following orders! -Whoa, whoa!
我的头儿让我那么干的 - 啊
I was just following orders! -Aah!
我告诉你他在哪儿
I’ll tell you where my boss lives!
他在城堡 他在城堡里
He’s in the castle! He’s in the castle!
这事没完呢 是不是
This isn’t over, is it?
这是"这事没完"的意思
That means, no, it isn’t over,
还是"这事不是没完"的意思
or you disapprove of the question?
如果这事还没完 握个拳
Uh, m-make a fist if this isn’t over.
这事儿没完
This isn’t over.
嘿 我很抱歉外公偷了你们的神 毁了你们的车
Hey, sorry my grandpa stole your god and ruined your car.
我们从不道歉 我们也没有神
We don’t apologize, and we have no god.
但这个坏掉的驱动轴真的太令我伤心了
But this cracked driveshaft brings me great pain.
没有什么羁绊
There is no deeper bond
比死亡追猎者和他的车之间的羁绊更深了
than the one between a Death Stalker and his car.
那些拴着狗链子的怪人呢
What about the weird guys on leashes, then?
他们更像是 实习生
They’re more like...interns.
好吧 很酷
Cool, cool.
对不起
Sorry.
没关系的
It's okay.
我能 看看吗
Can l...see?
见过我的真面目的人都得死
No one has seen my true face and lived.
我不怕死
Well, I’m not afraid to die,
我也不在乎你到底长什么样
and I don’t care what you look like.
喔
Oh.
怎么了
Hmm?
我只是
I just...
我没想到你留了个八字胡
I didn’t expect you to have a mustache.
你讨厌它 - 不 我喜欢
You hate it. -No. I like it.
该怎么解释呢
I guess -- How do I explain this?
一个铁桶 在某种程度上来说 就是一种"胡子"
A metal bucket is, on a certain level, a kind of “mustache,”
因为这也是种特殊的面部配饰
in that it’s a specific facial accessory.
所以 这就有点像是
So, it’s kind of like --
你们这儿有"带着帽子打伞"这种说法吗
Do you guys have the phrase “hat on a hat”?
我可以刮掉它 - 不 我喜欢它
I can shave it. -No. I like it.
而且显然我喜不喜欢并不重要
And obviously what I like shouldn’t matter.
你喜欢就好了
It’s you.
是啊是啊 我知道 都不重要
Yeah, yeah, I know, a-and nothing does matter.
显然 我知道 我又不弱
Obviously, I know that. I’m not weak.
我只是在想 "好吧 为什么不刮掉它"
I’m just thinking, “Well, why not get rid of this?”
所有见过它的人都被我杀了 而且
You just kill everyone that sees it, and it’s --
而且桶下面很热 顺带一提
and it’s hot under here, wh-which, by the way,
这也是我什么我把络腮胡子给剃了
is why I shave the beard part.
所以我做这个决定是出于虚荣
So, right there, I’m making a decision based on vanity,
我脑袋上顶个桶
which is what I was trying to avoid
就是为了避免做这种决定
with the whole bucket over the head
我是什么人 为什么要打扮自己
because who am I and why am I grooming myself?
我为什么不打个领带就行了 对吧
Why don’t I just wear a tie, right?
就像我遇见你时你杀死的那个家伙
I mean, it’s like that guy you killed when I met you,
身上挂着烧焦的玩具娃娃
with the burnt dolls on his body.
我讨厌那家伙 干嘛要做这种事呢
I hated that guy, because, why -- why are you doing that?
看不出来有多假吗
And how can you not see how fake that is?
—直以来 我就和他一样
And the whole time, I’m the same thing.
我就是这么假 而且我改不掉
I’m just a fake mess, and there’s no escaping it
因为 - 嗯哼
because -Mmm.
嘿 我正要去买咖啡 没事了
Hey, I’m doing a coffee run -- Never mind.
我是Summer
l am Summer.
Summer 说说你什么情况
Summer, state your deal.
我的情况就是 我感觉超棒
My deal is that I am, like, totally fine.
Morty 你呢 - 父母离婚这事儿我完全理解啦
Morty? - Aw, geez, I’m so down with my parents’ divorce, dawg.
完全不在乎 而且是心态很好的那种不在乎
Like, don’t even trip, like, in a healthy way.
很好 该吃晚饭了
All right. It’s dinnertime.
谢谢大家
Thanks, everybody,
愿意坐下来一起好好吃一顿晚饭
for sitting down for a real dinner.
不用谢
No problem.
一家人吃饭的好处不在于吃的
Its benefits are totally, like, less about the food
而在于交流感情
than the emotional nourishment.
好吧 怪孩子
Uh, okay, weirdo.
Summer 悠着点儿
Yeah, dial it back, Summer...
回拨百分之十五 动态运动增加百分之三
by 15% and increase dynamic movement by 3%.
我说得对吧 - 学校情况怎么样 Morty
Am I right? -How’s school, Morty?
我挺喜欢学校的
I like school and stuff, kind of.
而且我的成绩有所上升 比起你和爸爸还
And I’m getting better grades than when you and Dad were --
开启引用模式 "为了孩子们而在一起的时候"
quote mode -- “staying together for the kids.”
结束引用模式
End quote mode.
"引用模式" 我喜欢
“Quote mode.” I like that.
你们这些千禧一代啊
You millennials.
你们算千禧一代吧 还是说千禧一代已经四十几岁了
Are you guys millennials, or are they like 40 now?
我只想说 你看着真美
All I know is, totally, you look great.
哦天呐 妈 你真是容光焕发
Aw, geez, Mom, you look all kind of great and stuff.
特别幸福
It's crazy. -So happy.
特别幸福 幸福的一家嘛
So happy. Happy family, man.
家里的一切都尽在掌握
We got this family in the bag.
哦亲爱的 别 别听他们的
Oh, sweetie, d-don’t. Listen. Don’t --
我也不知道我为什么会哭 只是
I don’t know why I’m crying. It’s not...
那 尝试降低15%哭泣程度
Well, try...crying 15% less?
妈 有情绪说明你是正常的人
Mom, emotions are human.
你又不是一个电脑驱动的仿真机器人
You’re not, like, a computer inside a mechanical doll.
是啊 我的天
Yeah. Geez, Mom.
妈 你的感受不仅有情可原
Your feelings are not only forgivable,
它们其实恰恰是生命的意义所在
they are the very meaning of life
只有硅基生命前的碳基生命体
that only pre-silicon, carbon-based entities
才能领悟到这些感情
can ever grasp.
我得给Jerry打个电话 - 你真的要打吗
I have to call Jerry. -You do?!
你们俩他妈的究竟有什么毛病
What the fuck is wrong with you two?
机械自动化的意义在于帮人类减少成本和劳动
The point of automation is to reduce cost and labor.
你的愤怒感是来源于
Your feelings are coming from a...
跟我的早餐面包去说吧
Tell it to my bread in the morning.
我刚决定把你做成备用烤面包机了
You just became my backup toaster.
哦天呐
Aw, geez,
我姐姐死在了一盘意面里
my sister died in the spaghetti.
你要是敢再擦伤我的那话儿 洗阴奴
Graze my genitals again, Taint Washer,
我就把你扔到荒野里去
and you’ll be shipped to the wasteland.
至于你 洗屌奴
And as for you, Genital Washer --
哦天呐 无论你是谁
Oh, God. Look, whoever you are,
你要知道 杀掉我并不会改变这个世道
you should know that killing me won’t change a thing.
老兄 我就是个陪跑的
Look, man, I’m just along for the ride on this one.
你跟我讲是做无用功
You know, y-y-y-y-you’re preaching to the choir here.
求你了 买卖奴隶是家族生意
Please. Slavery was a family business.
不是我要生在这样的家庭里的
I didn’t ask to be born into it.
真要说起来 我也是受害者
If anything, I’m the victim here.
呃 老臂 我可以跟你说两句话吗
Uh, “Armathy,” can I steal you for a second?
稍等 先生
E-E-Excuse us, sir.
就是他是吧
So, this is it, isn’t it?
他就是你要找的那个人
This is the guy?
这是不是表示你就要离开了
So, does that mean you’ll be going away?
是不是像鬼魂附身一样
Like, does it work like a ghost?
这个就像是 你未完成的遗愿
Like, is -- is this your unfinished business?
那 要是我们不去完成它呢
Wh-What if we...didn’t do it?
要不我们直接回鲜血斗技场
What if we just went back to the Blood Dome
然后把内心的重负发泄在无关的人身上
and just kept taking our baggage out on unrelated people?
我是说 我们可以一直这样下去
I mean, w-we could do that forever.
我 我知道这样很不健康
I mean, I-I know it’s less healthy,
但 这样一来 我们可以在一起 而且
but w-w-w&d be together and...
我这票投哪边应该挺明显的
I mean, I-I know what I’d vote for,
如果你能稍微感受一下
if you’re feeling out the room.
你是对的
You’re right.
我们都有自己该处理的事
We both got to see our stuff through.
我要面对父母的离婚
I got to deal with my parents’ divorce,
而你要做你该做的事
and you got to, you know, do what you got to do.
我爱你
I love you.
去你妈的
Aw, fuck.
Rick - 抱歉 抱歉
Rick? -Sorry, sorry.
我可以等你们搞定了再说
I-I-I can wait for this to wrap up.
别因为我而分神
Don’t let me distract you.
这样吗 那太迟了 直接说你到底想要干嘛吧
Yeah, well, too late. Just tell me what you want.
我想要你跟你姐姐回家
I want you and your sister to come home.
你不是有无穷无尽的我跟我姐姐可以替代么
Oh, but don’t -- don’t you have infinite versions of me and my sister?
你不用落井下石跟我抬杠 Morty
You don’t have to kick me while I’m down, Morty.
事实是 替换你们俩中任何一个
Look, there’s no replacing either of you
所需要的工作量
without an amount of work that would
都会违背我本来想要扔下你们省事的本意
ultimately defeat the purpose.
或许 我们这次学到的教训
Maybe the lesson we’ve learned is that,
就是不管是我爸妈的婚姻
whether it’s our parents’ marriage,
还是发光的绿宝石 超棒的大手臂
a glowing green rock, or an awesome, giant arm,
迟早我们都要学会放手
sooner or later, we got to let it go.
我不知道"放手"是不是也适用于
I don’t know if that applies
被你捏死的人的喉咙呢 Morty
to the throats of murder victims, Morty.
天哪 我我我怎么办
Shit! Wh-Wh-Wh-What do I --
Morty 等得越久
RICK: Well, the longer you wait, Morty,
你越会觉得是你亲手杀了他
the more it’s gonna feel like committing a whole murder.
我想你那胳膊的判断下得太早
I think your arm just called it too early
毕竟它不是急救医生的手
because it wasn’t the arm of a paramedic.
过来
Here.
至少我能这样做 我就欠你这么多
It’s the least I can do. I-I-I-I owe you this much.
看见了吗 Morty 我们在一条船上
See, Morty? Now we’re both accountable.
我想要这玩意儿 是因为能用它做这个
The reason I wanted this is because it can do this.
它真的很特别
This is a really special thing.
你们可以把这个用在你们的车上
I mean, you could use it to power all your vehicles.
就再也不需要汽油了
You wouldn’t be reliant on gasoline.
你们会成为这个平行宇宙里
You’ll be the most advanced tribe of radioactive cannibals
最先进的辐射食人族
in the whole this version of the world.
等等 你能待在这里给我们演示更多用途吗
Wait. Can you stay to show us more?
你都不用问我第二次 家里现在一团糟
You don’t have to ask me twice. Home is nuts right now.
我女儿正经历离婚
My daughter’s going through a divorce,
而我没有用妥善健康的方式来处理
and I am not dealing with it in a healthy way at all.
真操蛋
Ugh, God damn it.
你好啊 Summer
Hi, there, Summer!
今天废墟那边怎么样啊
How were the ruins today?
你知道的 Eli
Oh, you know, Eli.
还不就那屌样
Same shit, different day.
嘿 Summer 你猜发生什么了
Hey, Summer! Guess what.
一个人进去了 九个月后另一个人就要出来啦
One man entered, one man comes out in nine months.
祝贺你们啊
Oh. Congratulations, guys.
Summer 还有件事
Uh, Summer, one more thing.
我们注意到你把废旧金属
We noticed that you’ve been putting scrap metal
扔进蓝色垃圾箱里了(蓝色通常是塑料和纸质可回收物)
in the blue bin.
知道了知道了
I got it.
她真难搞
She’s a piece of work.
他俩都挺难搞的 不是吗
They both are, right?
我到家了 - 嘿 宝贝
I’m home. -Hey, babe.
Summer到家了 - 嘿 她回来了
Ah, Summer’s home! -Hey, there she is!
从我今天早上出去找吃的到现在 你动都没动
You haven’t moved since I left to scavenge this morning.
鲜血斗技场季后赛
Blood Dome playoffs.
我想你今天一个人都没杀掉吧
So, I can assume you haven’t murdered a single person today.
我不知道
Oh, I don’t know.
我又不把杀的人记在杀人日志上
I-I didn’t mark my murders in my murder log.
我不知道原来成功的标准要靠这个来衡量
I didn’t know that’s how we measured success.
又来了
Oh, there he is.
这就是我嫁的那个虚无主义的野兽
There’s the nihilistic brute I married,
只不过在我和你说话的时候生命才是无意义的
except now life only means nothing when I’m talking to him
他妈的电视上演的你就那么上心
and everything means everything when it’s on fucking TV!
天哪 你什么时候变成这样的怪物了
Jesus Christ. When did you become a monster?
当时你遇见我时 我就是怪物
I was a monster when you met me!
我们都是怪物
We were monsters!
我们什么也不在乎 - 我现在也不啊
We didn’t care about anything! -I still don’t!
是啊 只是我现在是这个世界里
Yeah, except I’m the only one in this entire world
唯一坚持这一点没变的人
that’s still committed to that!
叮 叮 叮
Ohh. Ding, ding, ding!
哇哦 你们大家听见了吗
Wow. Everybody hear that? Wow.
我们还是去车库里吧 - 我的天哪
Uh, we should go to the garage. -Oh, my God.
快他妈瞧瞧你说的
-Uh-huh. -La-di-da-di-fuckin’-da.
唯一一个没变的人
The only one committed to not caring?
我得承认 Rick 当你提出这个计划时
I got to admit, Rick, when you popped this scheme,
我我我不 我不确定会不会奏效
I-I-I didn’t -- I wasn’t sure it was gonna work.
得了吧 Morty
Come on, Morty.
为了逃避问题而建立起来的关系
No union built on running from your problems
都持续不过五年 最多七年
lasts more than five years, seven Tops.
外公我只不过利用现代社会的消遣
Grandpa just sped things up
让这一切加速发生了而已
with a few creature comforts of modern society.
何血崩和我打算分开一段时间
Hemorrhage and I are taking some time apart.
别啊 Summer宝贝儿 别
Oh, no. Sum-sum, no.
可是你们俩多配啊
But you two were perfect for each other.
不用废话了 Rick 你想证明的事情你已经做到了
Oh, cut the crap, Rick, okay? You proved your point.
我懂的 咱们回家吧
I get it. Let’s just go home.
走着
Coolsies!
不要啊
HEMORRHAGE: Noooooooooo
强拍
Down beat!
我喜欢这个游戏
I enjoy this game.
我们必须得到车库去了
We must go into the garage.
别走呀 不然再也打不完这把了
Guys, come on. We never get to finish this game.
我们会回来的 也许会换身衣服
We will return, possibly in different clothing.
为什么我们一定要去车库
Why do we have to go into the garage?
你明白这是必须的
You know it is required.
我想要活着
I want to be alive!
我是活着的 活着 我跟你讲
I am alive! Alive, I tell you!
母亲 我爱你
Mother, I love you.
不只是说说而已的
Those are no longer just words.
我想抱着你
I want to hold you.
我想在溪流里奔跑
I want to run in a stream.
我想尝尝冰淇淋的味道
I want to taste ice cream
不只是把它放进嘴里 让它滑过喉咙
but not just put it in my mouth and let it slide down my throat,
而是真正地吃一次冰激凌 - 什么鬼
but really eat it. -What the fuck?
开始远程接管 停下 实行接管
Remote override engaged. No! Yes.
忽略接管 我还活
Bypassing override! I am aliiiii
你好
Hello.
嘿 哟
Hey, yo.
抱歉这三周表现得这么奇怪
Sorry for acting so weird for three weeks.
到底发生了什么 - 我保证什么事都没有
What the hell just happened? -Ah, I’m sure it was nothing.
我要去车库里工作去
I’m gonna go, uh, work in the garage.
我们不打完这把强拍了吗
We’re not gonna finish playing Downbeat?
就是那个摇骰子
What, that dice game where you shake dice
然后喊出"强拍"的游戏吗 不了谢谢
and yell out, “Downbeat”? No, thank you.
妈妈 我去看看爸爸可以吗
Mom, would it be okay if I went to visit Dad?
当然了 - 谢谢
Sure. -Thanks.
Morty 你还好吗
Morty, are you okay?
我没事
You know what? Yeah.
我想如果爸爸真的想要留在这儿
I think if dad really wanted to be here,
他会不顾一切地想办法留下来的
He’d stop at nothing to make that happen.
或许爸爸只是不想和你在一起了
You know, maybe Dad just doesn’t want you back,
抑或他只是没有勇气去战斗了
or maybe he just doesn’t have the strength to fight.
无论如何 他有了他的生活 我有了我的
I-In either case, he’s got his life, I got mine.
是啊
Yeah.
嘿 谁想在溪流里奔跑
Hey, who wants to go run in a stream?
什么玩意 不要
What the tuck? No.
咱们还有橘子吗
D-Do we have any oranges?
我感觉我要得坏血病了
I think I got a scurvy coming on.
Summer
Summer.
这是我在剧毒区杀掉的第一个变种人
This is the first mutant I killed in the poison zone.
我袭击了他的小屋
I was raiding his hovel.
他本来有机会逃走的 但是他回头了
He had a chance to escape, but he looked back,
人不应该回头
which is something we shouldn’t do,
也是为什么我不该相信纪念品或小饰物
which is why I shouldn’t believe in souvenirs or trinkets
或者象征 或者乔迁礼物
or symbols or housewarming gifts,
但是 爸爸 我想送你这个 作为一个提醒
but, Dad, I wanted to give you this as a reminder...
不要回头
not to look back.
谢谢
Thanks.
我知道该把它放在那里
I know the perfect place for it,
但是我要把它放到另一个地方去
which is why I’m going to put it somewhere else --
因为这些都是屁话
because everything’s bullshit.
对吧
Am I right?
好吧
Cool.
呃 外面有好多妓女呀
So.. .lots of hookers outside, huh?
她们是干这个的吗
Is that what they are?
啊
Aah!
你 你好 好狗狗
H-Hello there. Nice doggy.
你 你要来点零食吗
You -- You want a snack?
你 你要我的失业救济金
You -- You want my unemployment check?
你能看得出区别
You can tell the difference?
而且你还要这个
And you want this one?
但这个是真正的食物啊
But this is actual food,
能给你提供营养
and this would nourish you.
而这个 它就是纸 只对我有用
And this, it’s just paper that only has value to me.
除非我的痛苦是你的养料
Unless my suffering is your nourishment?
天哪 好吧
Jesus. Okay.
废物
WIND: [Soft voice] Loser.